是时候了 去召集军团吧
Summon the legions. It is time.
我们的敌人扬言要发起进攻
Our enemy vows to attack.
你们当中有谁愿意奋起作战
Who among you will stand and fight?
你们会死的
You will die.
这一天我已经等待很久了
Long have I awaited this day.
我向索隆宣誓效忠
I pledge my loyalty to Sauron.
我们的人已经走了一半
Half of us just left.
但还有一半选择了留下
But half stayed.
为什么没有选我
Why wasn't I chosen for the expedition?
我以为你要去西部
Thought you were going west.
我要先做点配得上努门诺尔人做的事
Not till I've done something worthy of Númenor.
我刚刚说服努门诺尔派出五艘船
I have just convinced Númenor to send five ships
和五百人来帮助你的人民
and 500 men to aid your people
帮你加冕为王
and place a crown upon your head.
你是在要我去一个 我发誓永远不会回去的地方
You are asking me to go to the one place that I swore never to return.
你为什么要一直战斗
Why do you keep fighting?
因为我停不下来
Because I cannot stop.
跟我一起去 一起拯救我们俩的种族
Come with me, and together we will redeem both our bloodlines.
我们朝东北方向行进 前往中洲
We head nor'-east. For Middle-earth.
这并不是剑 而是一种力量
It is no sword. It is a power.
你听说过索隆吗
Have you heard of Sauron?
我以前见过这个
I've seen this before.
这是一把钥匙
It is a key.
敌方指挥官说过 要在这些土地上给奥克一个家
The enemy commander spoke of giving the Orcs a home in these lands.
但不管他有什么阴谋 有一点是肯定的
Whatever his design, this much is certain.
敌人知道你儿子 有他需要用来启动计划的东西
Our enemy knows your son has what he needs to enact it.
要多久
How long?
可能是几个小时
Maybe hours.
指环王：力量之戒
第一季第六集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
新生命
New life.
蔑视死亡
In defiance of death.
孩子们
My children,
我们经受了艰辛无数
we have endured much.
我们挣脱了枷锁
We cast off our shackles.
越过高山和原野
Crossed mountain, field,
穿过严寒和荒地
frost, and fallow
直到我们脚上的血染湿了地上的泥
till our feet bloodied the dirt.
从灰色山脉到埃斐尔阿尔能
From Ered Mithrin to the Ephel Arnen,
我们都坚持下来了
we have endured.
但今晚 还有一场考验在等着我们
Yet tonight, one more trial awaits us.
或许敌人实力很弱 而且为数不多
Our enemy may be weak, their numbers meager...
但明天黎明之前 我们当中会有一部分奥克倒下
...yet before this night is through, some of us will fall.
但如果你们这次倒下
But for the first time,
将不再是远方大地上籍籍无名的奴隶
you do so not as unnamed slaves in far-away lands,
而是首次以兄弟的身份
but as brothers.
以兄弟姐妹的身份 在属于我们自己的土地上倒下
As brothers and sisters in our home!
战斗
Nampat.
Nampat! Nampat!
因为就在今夜 我们将伸出乌鲁克族的铁拳
This is the night we reach out the iron hand of the Uruk...
握紧双拳夺回这片土地
...and close our fist around these lands.
战斗
-Nampat!
给我搜
Search it.
全体注意 散开 把他们找出来
All of you! Fan out! Find them!
父亲大人 我无意冒犯 但敢问索隆在哪里
Meaning no offense, Lord-father, but where is he?
他出什么事了
What happened to Sauron?
找不到他的丝毫踪迹 他肯定是学聪明逃走了
Can't find tooth nor tail of him. Must've got smart and scarpered.
不会的 那个精灵就在这里
No. The Elf's here.
我闻到他的气味了
I smell him.
遵命 父亲
Yes, Father.
在这上边
Up here!
把他拿下
Bring him down!
马上撤出去
Get out, now!
把那扇门打开
Open that door!
快出去
Get out!
父亲大人 您得立刻离开
Lord-father! You must move now!
您得离开
You must move!
这么大的火 能侥幸活下来的奥克能有多少
How many of 'em could have survived that?
我们有多少时间
How long do we have?
并没有多少
Not long enough.
来吧 我们得把村子武装起来
Come on, we have to make ready the village.
慢点 贝雷克 别激动
Easy, Berek. Easy, boy.
把它吊起来
Hoist it up!
我以为所有士兵都上床睡觉了
I thought all soldiers were to be abed.
请原谅我 指挥官 我只是…
Pardon me, Commander. I... I was only...
想第一个看到大陆
Hoping to get the first sight of land?
稍息
At ease.
过一会儿你就能看到了
It'll be visible to your eyes in a few moments.
难道说你已经看到了吗
Is it visible to yours already?
大约一个小时前我就看到了
Has been for nearly an hour.
精灵的眼神真是犀利
Keen are the eyes of the Elves.
可是我却从没见过你
And yet, mine have not before seen you.
没见过你舞剑也没见过你扬帆
Swinging steel nor flying sail.
你是什么军衔
What is your rank?
我负责清扫马厩
Stable sweep.
不要瞧不起这种 能让人学会谦逊的劳苦工作
Despise not the labor which humbles the heart.
对于整个王国来说 满招损谦受益
Humility has saved entire kingdoms the proud have all but led to ruin.
我加入远征军 可不是为了来学习谦逊的 指挥官
I did not join this expedition to be humbled, Commander.
那你加入的目的是什么 士兵
Then for what did you join, soldier?
我只是想离开
I was just trying to get away.
尽可能远离那个地方
As far as I could from that place.
努门诺尔吗
Númenor?
不是努门诺尔
It's not Númenor.
反正不是真正的努门诺尔
Not the real Númenor, anyway.
真正的努门诺尔根本没存在过
If it ever existed.
它存在过
It existed.
而且仍然存在…
It exists still...
哪怕只存在于最下层的 马厩清洁工心里
If only in the heart of the lowliest stable sweep.
我叫伊熙尔杜
It's Isildur.
我早该看出来
I might have known.
你长得像你父亲
You have the look of your father.
人们总说我长得更像我母亲
I was always told I look more like my mother.
士兵
Soldier.
船长
Captain.
他母亲…
His mother...
她出什么事了
What happened to her?
很奇怪
It is strange.
我大半辈子 望向东方都是见旭日从海面上升起
Most of my life, I've looked east to see the Sun rise over the sea.
望向西方见夕阳落到地平线下
And west to see it set over the land.
虽然我们正驶向黎明 但对我而言
We're sailing into the dawn, and yet, to me,
感觉却像夜幕即将降临
it feels like the coming of night.
她是淹死的
She drowned.
已经看到陆地了 陛下
Land has been sighted, Your Majesty.
我们多久才能抛锚停泊
How long before we make anchor?
要航行一整天才能进入山区
It's a full day's sail into the mountains.
从那里出发 要向东再骑一天才能进入山谷
And from there, another day's ride east into the vale.
给其他船发信号
Signal the other ships.
告诉他们尽可能加快速度
Tell them to make all possible haste.
以我们的能力无法毁掉它
It is beyond our skill to destroy.
你要把它藏在哪
Where will you hide it?
不能让任何人知道
No one must know.
就连你也不行
Not even you.
我们已经发现了敌人
Our enemy has been sighted.
上一次我们活了下来
We survived them before.
这次我们也必将战胜敌人
Now we must do so again.
今晚
Tonight.
我们的位置很有利
Our position gives us an advantage.
但要想利用这个优势 必须把敌人引到近处
But to use it, we must draw the enemy in close.
我们必须等到所有奥克
We must wait until every last Orc
跨过那座桥之后 再发起进攻
has crossed that bridge to spring our attack.
这将会考验你们的勇气
This will test your nerve.
放马过来吧
Let it.
所有无法战斗的人员将在里边驻守
All who cannot fight will be barricaded inside.
这里将是我们的要塞和撤退据点
This is to be our keep. Our fallback point.
大家都要鼓起勇气
-Take heart. All of you.
我见过许多军队以少胜多
I have seen smaller armies defeat greater foes.
太阳很快就要落山了
Soon, the sun will set.
我向你们保证 只要守好自己的岗位 就能见到明天的日出
Do your part, and I swear to you, you shall see it rise again.
-你们相信吗  -相信
-Do you believe it? -Aye.
-Do you believe it? -Aye!
各就各位
To your positions.
那我呢
What about me?
你去小酒馆
Tavern.
伤员和儿童才去小酒馆 我可以战斗
Tavern's for wounded and children. I can fight.
我知道你可以
I know you can.
所以我才要你去那里 保护无法战斗的人
Which is why I need you in there, protecting those who cannot.
来吧
Come.
我小时候经常会做各种噩梦 你记得吗
Remember when I was little... When I used to have bad dreams?
我记得
I remember.
还记得你是怎么安慰我的吗
You remember what you used to say?
就是你在黑暗中抱着我说的那番话
When you would hold me in the dark?
现在能再说给我听吗
Would you say it to me now?
“魔影终究只是渺小之物 且会逝去
"In the end, this shadow is but a small and passing thing.
“而在魔影无法触及之处
"There is light and high beauty
“光明与崇高之美永存
"forever beyond its reach.
“去寻找光明吧…
"Find the light...
“如此魔影便永远不得临身”
"And the shadow will not find you."
再见 妈妈
Farewell, Mother.
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
没有 你呢
No. Are you?
阿尔费林种子…
The alfirin seeds...
这是精灵的一项传统
It is a tradition among Elves.
每逢战争开始之前 种下一颗阿尔费林种子
Before the battle begins, plant one.
新生命 蔑视死亡
New life, in defiance of death?
精灵族相信 有一位维拉
It is believed that one of the Valar
会照看生长的植物…
watches over growing things...
以及植物的播种者
And those who tend them.
其余的种子…
The rest...
我们等战争结束后再来种
we shall plant after the battle is over.
种在一个新花园里
In a new garden.
你和我
You and I.
还有希奥
And Theo.
我们一起种
Together.
一言为定
Promise me.
他们来了
-They're here.
我的天…
Oh, dear...
那群蠢货没打中我们
The bleeding fools missed us.
来吧
Come on!
他们正朝小酒馆走去
They're headed for the tavern.
-为南方大地而战  -为南方大地而战
-Fight for the Southlands! -Fight for the Southlands!
这片土地是我们的
The land is ours!
非常勇敢啊 精灵 很勇敢
More than a bit brave, Elf. More than a bit.
布隆温
Bronwyn.
我们刚才是在与自己人战斗
We were fighting our own.
你们以为我们会白白收留他们
Thought we'd take 'em in for nothin'?
必须付出代价…
Had to pay the toll...
你们所有人都要付出代价
And now, all of you will.
特雷德威尔
Tredwill!
妈妈
Mother!
所有人 躲进要塞
Everyone, to the keep!
快走
Go! Go!
进小酒馆里
Into the tavern!
小酒馆
The tavern!
所有人
All of you!
快走
Go!
放桌子上
-The table!
快点
-Hurry!
妈妈
-Mother. Mother.
先救他
Help him first.
不要啊
No.
我们会救你的
We will help you.
妈妈
Mother.
希奥…
Theo...
你必须赶快止血
You'll have to stem the bleeding.
我不会…
I... I don't think I...
要么你来止血 要么我就会死 你明白吗
Either you're gonna do this or I'm gonna die. Do you understand?
希奥
Theo.
妈妈 你做好准备
Mother, prepare yourself.
对不起
I am sorry.
用力压住伤口
Put pressure on the wound.
烧…
Burn...
她失血过多 身体发冷
She's cold. She's lost too much blood.
不要
No. No. No.
她说了：“烧”
She's saying "burn."
阿尔费林种子 我们必须用火把止住伤口出血
The alfirin seeds. We have to seal the wound with fire.
给我拿一些点燃的木头过来 快
Bring me some burning wood. Hurry!
现在
Now.
就是现在
现在换这边
Now this side.
继续
Go on.
够了
That's enough.
布隆温
Bronwyn?
-妈妈  -布隆温
-Mother? -Bronwyn?
醒醒 妈妈
Wake up! Mother!
战斗
Nampat!
- 踢他们的后背 - 战斗
-Kick 'em in the back! -Nampat!
坐下
-Sit down!
我要找的东西
What I seek.
把它交给我
Give it to me.
先把他们放了
Let them go.
然后我才会考虑
I will consider it.
何苦为了这么点小东西 搭上他们的性命
Why sacrifice their lives for such a little thing?
下一个是那个女人
The woman next.
不要
No!
-等等  -希奥
-Wait! -Theo!
在这下边
It's under here.
不要
No.
希奥
Theo!
对不起
I'm sorry.
沃德雷格 我有个任务要交给你
Waldreg, I have a task for you.
他们全都得死
They all must die.
安塔摩
Ontamo!
去吧
Go.
Hyah!
父亲
Father!
-我没事 -我以为你…
-I'm all right. -I thought you...
我没事的 伊熙尔杜
I'm all right, Isil.
士兵
Soldier.
他们的指挥官呢
Their commander?
他手上的东西…
The item he possesses...
绝对不能让他带走
He must not escape with it.
那是谁
Who is that?
北征军的指挥官
Commander of the Northern Armies.
加拉德瑞尔
Galadriel.
跑快点
Noro lim!
快
Go!
你记得我吗
You remember me?
不记得
No.
住手
Stop!
我们需要留他一命
We need him alive.
我需要留他一命
I need him alive.
你不知道他干过什么事
You don't know what he did.
我伤害过你爱的人吗
Did I cause someone you love pain?
是个女人吗
A woman?
或许是个孩子
Perhaps a child?
闭嘴
Eat your tongue.
哈尔布兰德 把剑放下
Halbrand, put it down.
区区复仇远远无法让人满足
One cannot satisfy thirst by drinking sea water.
那么 你觉得怎么样
So, what do you think?
我喜欢这些山
I like the mountains.
你马上就能近距离看这些山了
You're about to get a closer look at them.
指挥官加拉德瑞尔正在组建一支军队
Commander Galadriel's putting together a company
追踪逃走的奥克
to track down the Orcs that escaped,
我苦口婆心才为我们俩求得位置
and I managed to wheedle the pair of us a spot.
那安塔摩呢
What about Ontamo?
我想我可能会 在这里待一阵子 帮帮这些人
I think I might stay here for a while. Lend these folk a hand.
-这周的战争看够了  -恐怕是一辈子的战争都看够了
-Seen enough battle for a week? -More like a whole lifetime.
这支军队什么时候出发
This company, when's it set out?
还不确定 要等加拉德瑞尔先处理完阿达尔
Don't know for certain. Not till she's done with him.
我小的时候 听过很多精灵被魔苟斯带走的故事
When I was a child, I heard stories of Elves taken by Morgoth.
那些精灵被折磨 被扭曲
Tortured. Twisted.
他们被改造为 一种新的 被摧残的生命形式
Made into a new and ruined form of life.
你就是其中一员吧
You are one of them, are you not?
魔里昂多
The Moriondor.
黑暗之子
The Sons of the Dark.
第一批奥克
The first Orcs.
乌鲁克族
Uruk.
我们更喜欢自称“乌鲁克族”
We prefer "Uruk."
就连魔里昂多也是听令于主人的
Even Moriondor take orders from a master.
我要找你的主人
And I seek yours.
他在哪
Where is he?
索隆在哪
Where is Sauron?
或许我们应该让囚犯们晒晒太阳
Perhaps we should bring our prisoners into the sunlight.
魔苟斯战败后
After Morgoth's defeat,
你们称之为索隆的那一位…
the one you call Sauron...
致力于“治愈”中洲
Devoted himself to healing Middle-earth,
将被毁坏的土地 以完美的秩序重新聚拢在一起
bringing its ruined lands together in perfect order.
他试图打造一种力量
He sought to craft a power
并非来源于肉体…
not of the flesh...
而是让肉体受控于它
But over flesh.
一种不可见世界的力量
A power of the Unseen World.
他说服尽可能多的人随他向北行进
He bid as many as he could to follow him far north.
但虽然他竭尽所能…
But try as he might...
他还是缺少一样东西
Something was missing.
那就是黑暗知识的影子
A shadow of dark knowledge
一直隐藏着 就是不让他找到
that kept itself hidden, even from him.
哪怕他在求索的过程中 手上已经沾满无数鲜血
No matter how much blood he spilt in its pursuit.
对我来说…
Mmm. For my part...
为了帮助他实现愿望 我已经牺牲了足够多的孩子
I sacrificed enough of my children for his aspirations.
我把索隆撕碎了
I split him open.
我杀了他
I killed Sauron.
我不信你
I do not believe you.
你的整支军队都杀不掉索隆
You cannot believe an Uruk could do that
你当然不信一个乌鲁克就能做到
which your entire army could not.
我不相信你是这支军队唯一的主人
I cannot believe that you are this army's only master.
我的孩子们没有主人
My children have no master.
他们不是孩子 是奴隶
They are not children, they are slaves.
但他们每一个都有姓名 有内心
But each one has a name. A heart. A heart.
-由魔苟斯创造的内心 -我们都出自独一之神的手
-A heart created by Morgoth. -We are creations of The One,
出自秘火的主宰 跟你一样
Master of the Secret Fire, the same as you.
他们也值得拥有生命之息
As worthy of the breath of life,
也同样值得拥有家园
and just as worthy of a home.
很快…
Soon...
这片土地将会是我们的 到时候你就会明白
This land will be ours. Then, you will understand.
并不是
No.
你族群的存在就是个错误
Your kind was a mistake.
一群拙劣的仿制品
Made in mockery.
哪怕要花上一整个纪元 我也会发誓要将你们斩草除根
And even if it takes me all of this Age, I vow to eradicate every last one of you.
但我会让你活着
But you shall be kept alive,
好让你见证那一天
so that one day,
到时候我会用匕首刺入你中毒的心脏
before I drive my dagger into your poisoned heart,
我会在你尖尖的耳朵旁低语
I will whisper in your piked ear
你的后代已经死绝了
that all your offspring are dead
你种族的祸根将以你为终结
and the scourge of your kind ends with you.
看来我不是唯一一个还活着
It would seem I'm not the only Elf alive
但已经被黑暗所改变的精灵
who has been transformed by darkness.
也许你苦苦寻找的魔苟斯继任者
Perhaps your search for Morgoth's successor
会在你的镜子里寻见
should have ended in your own mirror.
也许我应该先杀了你 你这个奥克的奴隶贩子
Perhaps I shall begin by killing you, you slavering Orc.
加拉德瑞尔
Galadriel.
乌鲁克…
Uruk.
你是谁
Who are you?
谢谢你…
Thank you...
把我拉了回来
For pulling me back.
早前是你先把我拉了回来
Was you, pulled me back first.
不管他对你做了什么
Whatever it was he did to you,
也不管你做了什么…
and whatever it was you did...
都要放下
Be free of it.
我从不相信我能放下…
I never believed I could be...
直到今天
Until today.
与你并肩作战 我…
Fighting at your side, I...
我感觉…
I felt...
如果我能抓住这种感觉
If I could just hold on to that feeling,
时刻保留在我身边
keep it with me always,
并将它深深刻入我的灵魂 那么我…
bind it to my very being, then I...
我也感觉到了
I felt it, too.
哈尔布兰德大人 摄政女王想见您
-Lord Halbrand. The Queen Regent wishes to see you.
摄政女王
Queen Regent.
我欠你的…你让我的人民得以幸存
What I owe you... My people are alive because of you.
按照我的理解 他们之所以能活着是因为你
As I understand it, they're alive because of you.
我可没想过要扛起这份重担
A burden I never sought to take up.
只有极少数最优秀的领袖 才能扛此重任
Few of the finest leaders do.
但如果你想减轻这份负担
But if you would like some relief in carrying it,
我也许能帮上忙
I may be able to help.
陛下 您找我
You called for me, Your Majesty?
布隆温…
Bronwyn...
这位是哈尔布兰德大人
This is Lord Halbrand.
布隆温
Bronwyn.
是真的吗  你就是他们承诺给我们的那位国王
Is it true? Are you the king we were promised?
是的
Yes.
所有人致敬
All hail!
向南方大地真正的国王致敬
All hail to the true King of the Southlands!
这片土地上的人们 已经等待这一刻很久了
The men of these lands have awaited this moment a long time.
肯定没有精灵等得久
Not nearly so long as the Elves.
别折磨自己了
Do not torment yourself.
换做别人 很多人也会做同样的选择
Many might have done the same in your place.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我感到的不仅仅是内疚
It's not just guilt I feel.
还有一种失去感
It's loss.
失去感
Loss?
当它在我手中时
When it was in my hands,
我感觉…
I felt...
非常强大
Powerful.
那就摆脱掉它
Then rid yourself of it.
一劳永逸
Once and for all.
怎么摆脱
How?
交给努门诺尔
Give it to Númenor.
让他们在返航回家的途中扔进海里
To toss into the sea on their voyage home.
放轻松 贝雷克
-Easy. Berek, easy.
划伤了一点而已 你没事的
It's just a scratch. You're okay.
嘿…贝雷克
Hey, hey, hey. Berek.
小心点
-Careful.
帮帮忙
Athae...
冷静下来
no ídhui hí.
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
困扰它的并不是它身上的疼痛…
It's not his pain that's bothering him...
而是骑手的疼痛
But that of his rider.
我不觉得痛啊
-I'm not in pain.
当西方之地努门诺尔的马匹 进入战场时
When a horse of Westernesse rides into battle,
它会与骑乘的战士 形成一种牢不可破的纽带
he forms an unbreakable bond with the soldier he bears.
随着时间的推移 人马合一
In time, they become as one.
甚至能够了解彼此的内心深处
Even knowing the innermost feelings of each other's heart.
-你了解它的感受  -不了解
-You know his feelings? -No.
但它了解你的
He knows yours.
你是从哪里学到这些的
Where did you learn all this?
从你妈妈那里
From your mother.
你能教我吗
Think you could teach me?
乌顿…
Ud?n... Ud?n. Ud?n.
快找掩护
Take shelter!
女王
The Queen!
贝雷克
Berek!
维蓝迪尔
Valandil!
翻过墙去
Over the wall!
-希奥  -希奥
-Theo! -Theo!
字幕翻译：腐哥
创意监督 罗婷婷